Guide to the M/E/A/N/I/N/G Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
M/E/A/N/I/N/G records
1980-2004
YCAL MSS 993
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12.4
(14 boxes)
The M/E/A/N/I/N/G Records, which span 1980 to 2004, contain correspondence, manuscript drafts, reviews and publicity materials, business and financial papers, and computer disks related to the publication and operation of the journal.
Scope and Contents
The M/E/A/N/I/N/G Records include correspondence, writings, production files, financial records, and other papers related to the magazine, its twenty-fifth anniversary anthology, and online editions of the magazine. Research strengths include critical work addressing the visibility of women artists, sexuality and the arts, censorship, art world racism, the legacies of modernism, artists as mothers,and visual art in the digital age.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 13 (3.5 inch disks): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 14 (original faxes): Restricted fragile material. Photocopies of the faxes have been interfiled in the original locations.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Granary Books, Inc., on the Library Associates Fund, 2007.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Production Files. II. Correspondence. III. Business Files.
Biographical / Historical
Co-founded by Susan Bee and Mira Schor in 1986, M/E/A/N/I/N/G was an art publication by and for artists. The magazine focused on the visual arts, with an emphasis on feminism and painting, and also included essays from poets. Twenty issues were published in print between 1986 and 1996. An anthology was published by Duke University Press in 2000; since 2002 the magazine has been published online.
Granary Books, Inc.
- Production files, circa 1986-2004; Series I
  Arrangement
  Materials within this series maintain the original physical organization found at time of acquisition.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains materials related to M/E/A/N/I/N/G journal issues and the anthology. Materials within this series are organized under two headings: Journal Issues and Meaning Anthology.
  - Journal Issues
    - Meaning #1 drafts/publicity (Box 1)
    - Meaning #1 Proofs/MS, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - MEANING 1, 1986-11-24; 2007-ycal-5841-0001; 1 (Box 13)
        Conditions Governing Access
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
        Disk contents include contributor notes, authors' names, cover logo, Table of Contents, and articles related to Issue 1.
    - Meaning #1 Facs. (Box 1)
    - Meaning #2 Xerox (Box 1)
      - MEANING 2 back-up MIRA SCHOR MEANING 1 b-up., 1986-11-24; 2007-ycal-5841-0002; 1 (Box 13)
        Files containing contributor notes, authors' names, cover logo, Table of Contents, and articles relating to Issue 1. (Appears to be back-up of disk 2007-ycal-5841-0001.)
    - Meaning #2 MS, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Meaning #3 Xerox (Box 1)
    - Meaning #3 MS (Box 1)
    - Meaning #4 Xerox & MS (Box 1)
    - Meaning #4 MS (Box 1)
    - Meaning #5 MS/correspondence, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Meaning #6 MS/Correspondence, 1989; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Meaning #6 Xerox (Box 1)
    - Meaning #7 MS, 1990; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Meaning #8 Xerox (Box 2)
    - Meaning #8 MS, 1990; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Meaning #9 Xerox (Box 2)
    - Meaning #9 MS, 1990–1991
    - Meaning #10 MS, 1991; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Meaning #11 MS, 1991–1992; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Meaning #12 MS, 1992; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Meaning #13 Partial Xerox (Box 2)
    - Meaning #13 MS, 1992–1993; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Meaning #14 MS, 1993; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Meaning #14 edits/final printout, 1992–1993 (Box 3)
      - M/E/A/N/I/N/G A:\Flyer (Flyer 1993 #14), 1992-1993; 2007-ycal-5841-0003; 1 (Box 13)
        Files include a flyer with subscription information.
      - MEANING #14, 1993-09; 2007-ycal-5841-0004; 1 (Box 13)
        Files including a brochure and items related to Issue 14.
    - Meaning #15 MS, 1993–1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Meaning #16 MS, 1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Meaning #16, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Meaning #17 MS, 1993–1995; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Meaning #18 MS, 1994–1995; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Meaning #19/20 Business Info, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Meaning #19/20 MS, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Meaning #19/20 Index MS (Box 3)
    - Meaning #19/20 contributions, 1996; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - New Observations, 1996; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Meaning #19/20, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Meaning #19/20 copy (Box 4)
    - New Observations, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Meaning online, 2002–2003; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Meaning online issue #1 MS, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Meaning online issue #2 MS, 2002–2003; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Flyers for issues #1 and 2 (Box 4)
    - Flyer for issue #18 (Box 4)
    - flyers for Meaning (Box 4)
    - Misc. (Box 4)
    - Meaning/Logo/Design (Box 4)
    - Book/Contrib., 1996–2000 (Box 4)
    - Table of Contents and Sub/renewal forms (Box 4)
    - CPDA Barcode, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Reviews of Meaning, 1990–1996 (Box 4)
    - Reviews etc., 1999–2004 (Box 4)
    - Une Fois Une 1995/96 [MS] (Box 4)
    - MS of "Painting After Painting" (Box 4)
  - Meaning Anthology
    - Meaning Anthology Gordon & Breach, correspondence, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Meaning anthology contract Duke and expenses, 1999–2005 (Box 4)
    - Meaning book ads, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Meaning anthology – contrib. notes/addresses, 2000–2001 (Box 4)
    - Meaning book, 2001 (Box 5)
    - G&B book – anthology, correspondence, meaning, 1996–1997 (Box 5)
    - Meaning anthology manuscript stuff, 1997–2000; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Meaning anthology, manuscript version, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Meaning book, Lapis, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Duke contract, 1998–2001; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Meaning, eliminated pieces (Box 5)
    - Susan Bee, Meaning correspondence (Box 5)
    - Meaning anthology 1999, 1998–1999 (Box 5)
    - Meaning book correspondence, MS, reader reports, 1996–1999; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Duke royalties reports, 2003 (Box 6)
    - Meaning anthology manuscript, 1999–2000; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Meaning corrected page proofs, 1996–2000; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Gordon & Breach MS, 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Gordon & Breach MS – dropped pieces (Box 6)
    - Meaning book – copyedited MS, 2000?; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - M/E/A/N/I/N/G selections WP5.1 IBM Dec. 26.99, 1992-1999; 2007-ycal-5841-0007; 1 (Box 13)
      Files related to Meaning anthology, as well as editorial and business correspondence related to the magazine.
- Correspondence, 1986-2003; Series II
  Contains correspondence related to M/E/A/N/I/N/G journal issues.
  - Correspondence, 1992–1994; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1988–1997; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1987–2003; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1988–1990 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: Submissions, 1987 (Box 7)
  - General correspondence, 1995–1996; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1988–2002; 5 folders (Box 8)
  - Correspondence/Rejected MS, 1986–2000; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Correspondence/Rejected MS, 1991–1996; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Correspondence/Rejected MS, 1987–1995; 8 folders (Box 9)
  - Small Publications, 1987–1994 (Box 9)
  - Re: Literary Magazines (Box 9)
  - Meaning Misc, 1987–1988 (Box 9)
  - Meaning Early Subscribers, 1986–1998 (Box 9)
- Business Files, 1980-2000; Series III
  Materials include information related to grants, fundraising, billing, contacts, and distribution.
  - NY State Council on the Arts - grants material, 1987–1996 (Box 10)
  - NYSCA handbook, 1992 (Box 10)
  - NYSCA grants, 1988–1992 (Box 10)
  - Segue Foundation/Jerome Foundation, 1988–1990 (Box 10)
  - Segue Foundation Correspondence, 1989–1996; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - NEA evaluation workbook, 1992 (Box 10)
  - NEA info, 1983–1996; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Bills-Accounting, 1986–1994; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Grants correspondence, 1987–1991 (Box 10)
  - Fundraising, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Grant material and publishing information, 1988–1998 (Box 10)
  - Meaning grants/Fundraising, 1988–1995 (Box 10)
  - Distribution, 1987–1996; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Distribution correspondence, 1988–1995 (Box 10)
  - Distribution Bills, 1987–2000 (Box 11)
  - Distribution, 1998–2000 (Box 11)
  - Invoices, 1987–1996; 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Ibidem magazine, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Printed matter including catalogs, 1990–1996; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Segue distributing catalogs, 1991–1993 (Box 11)
  - Small Press Distribution, Inc. catalogs, 1990–1991 (Box 11)
  - New Hope International Review, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Rolodex, A-J, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Rolodex, K-Z, misc-Z, 9 folders (Box 12)
  - Mailing list Info, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Mailing List Copy, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Mailing list, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - MAILING LIST, 2007-ycal-5841-0005; 1 (Box 13)
  - M/E/A/N/I/N/G everything on hard disk June 4.93, 1980-1999; 2007-ycal-5841-0006; 1 (Box 13)
    Contains files related to Meaning magazine and anthology, business correspondence, and editorial correspondence.
  - entire M/E/A/N/I/N/G directory 1990-99 WP5.1 IBM copied Dec. 16.1999, 2007-ycal-5841-0008; 1 (Box 13)
- Restricted Fragile Materials
  - Thermofax originals (Box 14)